(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome back to English.
How'd my name is Marko?
- And my name is Katherine.
And today we are talking about
an important holiday, the world over.
- It's very important all over the
world, especially in the United States.
So let's take a look at this
holiday in vocabulary preview.
- Very capillary preview.
- So the name of the
holiday is Veterans Day.
So veteran.
- So what's a veteran?
- A veteran is a person
who has participated
in a war or in some
kind of military situation.
- Okay.
So Veterans Day is a day
where you commemorate
all the people that
fought in the different wars.
- Exactly.
A veteran doesn't have to
be a World War II veteran.
They could be a civil war
veteran or a Vietnam war veteran.
- Okay, so a Gulf War.
- Exactly.
- All right, so that's the
day in the United States
where everyone honors all
the soldiers that participated
in different wars and they
fought for their country.
All right, so why don't
we take a look at our
dialogue for the first
time and we'll be back.
(upbeat music)
- Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
- You mean, almost it's day.
- What are you talking about?
November 11th is Veterans Day.
What planet are you from?
- Well, as you know, on November 11th,
the Allies signed a
peace treaty with the
Germans, also known
as the Armistice Treaty.
This marked the end of World War I
and many countries around the world
commemorated this date and the
names such as Remembrance Day.
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
There's a lot going on
around the world on this day.
- Wow, I didn't know.
Probably because I've
flunked history in school.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so there's a lot of really
great vocabulary in this elementary lesson.
So let's take a look at some of these words
and phrases in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so the first word
that came up, after the guy
mentioned Veterans Day, the
girl mentioned Armistice Day.
Armistice.
- Okay, so what is this Armistice Day?
- Armistice means stop fighting, right?
So it's a time in which people
lay down their arms, we say.
And it's one that's celebrated
in Commonwealth countries
like England or Canada
and in parts of Europe.
- Okay, very good.
So Armistice Day, kind
of like the equivalent
for Commonwealth
countries to Veterans Day.
All right, and well, the girl
gave him a bit of a history
lesson and mentioned that on November 8th,
11th, the allies signed a peace treaty.
So we have two great words here, allies.
- So allies is a word
that we use in English
to indicate people who
fought against the Germans,
Italians, and Japanese in World War II.
So allies include Great
Britain, America, France.
- France for some time.
(laughs) - So these are
countries that were, and
Russia, they were fighting
against the Germans.
- Right, so, and in general
terms, an ally is a friend, right?
- Exactly, so the
opposition-- - Mark one our
allies, we, if there's a
fight, I'm on his side.
- The opposite of enemies.
- Exactly.
- Very good, and well, the
allies signed a peace treaty.
So what is a peace treaty?
- A treaty is a document
that outlines new rules
for a situation, and a peace treaty
is a document that calls for peace.
It says, we will not fight
anymore, we will have peace,
and this is what this
means, so we have new rules.
- So it's an agreement,
it's like a contract.
- Exactly, it's a contract between nations.
- Okay, very good.
All right, and as we
mentioned, Veterans Day,
or Armistice Day, we
commemorate these events
that happened in the past, so
to commemorate something.
- Right, so in a sense, we are honoring it,
so to commemorate is to remember,
to honor, to remember with respect.
- So yeah, to remember with respect,
exactly, there's a positive,
respectful tone here.
It's remembering for a good reason.
- Okay, very good.
So we've taken a look at these four words.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again,
and we'll be back in a bit
to look at the Lindsay Builder.
(upbeat music)
- Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
- You mean Armistice Day?
- What are you talking about?
November 11th is Veterans Day.
What planet are you from?
- Well, as you know, on November 11th,
the allies signed a
peace treaty with the
Germans, also known
as the Armistice Treaty.
This marked the end of World War
One, and many countries round the world,
commemorated this date on the
names, such as Remembrance Day.
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
There's a lot going on
around the world on this day.
- Wow, I didn't know, probably
because I flunked history in school.
(upbeat music)
- Today's Fluency Builder includes a couple
of really interesting phrases
that are kind of longer.
So let's take a look at the first one,
which is very, very common in English.
- All right, so this first
sentence was kind of using a
sarcastic tone, 'cause he said,
what are you talking about?
- Right, so this guy says Veterans Day, oh,
you mean Armistice Day,
what are you talking about?
That means no, I mean Veterans Day.
- Right, so he wasn't really asking,
like, what are you talking about?
He was literally saying, with this sentence,
are you crazy or like, you're wrong?
- You're wrong, okay.
- So what are you talking about
is a very sarcastic way to say, listen,
I think you're wrong, or you
must be a little bit crazy here.
- Right, what are you talking about?
- All right, and then to end the
whole sarcastic sentence there,
he said, what planet are you from?
- So obviously, this is Veterans
Day, what planet are you from?
So you're so wrong, how do
you not understand what this is?
- How do you not know this?
- Right, and so for example,
I could say, maybe I'll ask
you, Marco, who's the
president of the United States?
- All right, I can say, well,
what planet are you from?
It's obviously president Obama.
- Oh, duh.
- So it's like, obviously
everybody knows this,
since you're saying, how
do you not know this already?
- So it's very sarcastic,
what planet are you from?
- And finally, the guy is talking about how
he doesn't understand what the meaning
of Veterans Day is, and after this long
explanation, he says, well, I didn't know.
Probably because I've
flunked history in school.
- So if you flunked
history, or you flunked any
subject in school, it
means you didn't pass.
- Exactly, so flunked to flunk is a verb,
and in question, it
means to fail a subject.
That means maybe 100% is
perfect, you got 50% to 40%,
and you have to take the course again.
- Okay, did you ever
flunk an exam in school?
- No.
- You didn't ever. - No.
- Wow, such a good student.
- Did you?
- Maybe it did, maybe once or twice.
- I was much too self-critical.
(laughs)
- All right, let's listen to this dialogue
again, and we'll be back in a bit.
(upbeat music)
- Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
- You mean, almost, it's day.
- What are you talking about?
- November 11th is Veterans Day.
What planet are you from?
- Well, as you know, on November 11th,
the Allies signed a
peace treaty with the
Germans, also known
as the Armistice Treaty.
This marked the end of World War I, and
many countries round the world commemorate
this date and the names
such as Remembrance Day.
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
There's a lot going on
around the world on this day.
- Wow, I didn't know.
Probably because I
flunked history in school.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so Veterans Day, it's a
big deal in the United States, right?
- It's a very big deal in parade.
- Yeah, in most cities in
the country, they're parades,
and when I was in school, we had
to play music, 'cause I was in band.
We used to play music for the Veterans,
and we would go to the
cemetery and play taps.
(singing in foreign language)
- I know we would play tattoos.
- It's like the funeral song.
- Yeah, we would play
funeral songs and taps
for the local veterans who will be
respecting and commemorating fallen soldiers.
- Wow, and the President talks
as well like a national TV and stuff.
- That's right. - That's right.
- All right, so it's very interesting,
especially the history lesson, the fact that
on November, I think
it's called 11, 11, 11, right?
November 11 at 11 o'clock,
they signed this Armistice Treaty.
And that was in 1918,
so this is World War I.
We're talking about when the world had
never really seen fighting like this before,
and so everyone was
just relieved when what
they called the Great
War was finally over.
- It's a very interesting history lesson,
so I'm sure many people
have some opinions on this,
so we would be glad to hear it from
you on our website at englishpot.com.
You can also leave questions or
comments, and we'll see you guys there.
- And let us know, do you celebrate this holiday in your country?
- Yep, all right.
- Until next time, bye everyone.
(upbeat music)